Guide to the Horticultural Society of New York Records 1811-circa 2010 (bulk, 1900-circa 2010) MS 3033
New-York Historical Society
- Series VIII. Reference Files, 1850-2005; 211445; 8 Linear feet
  - Subseries VIII.B. Subjects, 1850-2006; 213271; 5 Linear feet
    - Subjects: C (10 of 11), 1850-2000; 213543 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 4)
      Companion plants
    - Subjects: C (11 of 11), 1850-2000; 213544 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 5)
      Compost
      Container gardens
      Corn
    - Subjects: D (1 of 3), 1900-2000; 211832 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 6)
      Delphinium
      Dianthus (carnations)
      Dionea (Venus fly trap)
      Dish gardens
      Dumbarton Oaks
      Dutch Elm Disease
    - Subjects: D (2 of 3), 1900-2000; 213546 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 7)
      Dutch Elm Disease (continued)
    - Subjects: D (3 of 3), 1900-2000; 213547 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 8)
      Drought gardening
      Dyes from plants
    - Subjects: E (1 of 3), 1920-2000; 211833 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 9)
      Echinacea
      Economic botany
      Edible landscaping
    - Subjects: E (2 of 3), 1920-2000; 213548 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 10)
      Elgin Botanic Garden
      Endangered species
    - Subjects: E (3 of 3), 1920-2000; 213549 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 11)
      England: gardens and parks
      Evergreens
    - Subjects: F (1 of 3), 1920-2000; 211851 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 1)
      Fences
      Floral clock
      Foundation planting
      Fountains
    - Subjects: F (2 of 3), 1920-2000; 213552 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 2)
      Fragrance gardens
      France: gardens and parks
      Freesia
    - Subjects: F (3 of 3), 1920-2000; 213553 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 3)
      Frick Museum garden
      Frost
      Fruit
    - Subjects: G (1 of 14), 1920-2000; 211854 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 4)
      Garden Conservation and Restoration
      Garden Design
    - Subjects: G (2 of 14), 1920-2000; 213554 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 5)
      Garden Design (continued)
    - Subjects: G (3 of 14), 1920-2000; 213555 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 6)
      Garden Furniture
    - Subjects: G (4 of 14), 1920-2000; 213556 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 7)
      Garden History
    - Subjects: G (5 of 14), 1920-2000; 213557 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 8)
      Garden Ornament
    - Subjects: G (6 of 14), 1920-2000; 213558 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 9)
      Garden Structures
      Garden Writing and Writers
    - Subjects: G (7 of 14), 1920-2000; 213559 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 10)
      Gates
      Gentianas
      Germany: gardens
    - Subjects: G (8 of 14), 1920-2000; 213560 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 11)
      Gladiolas
      Greenhouses
    - Subjects: G (9 of 14), 1920-2000; 213561 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 12)
      Greenhouses (continued)
    - Subjects: G (10 of 14), 1920-2000; 213562 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 13)
    - Subjects: G (11-14 of 14), 1920-2000; 213277 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 1-4)
    - Subjects: H (1 of 4), 1920-1980; 211894 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 5)
      Handicrafts
      Hardiness zones
    - Subjects: H (2 of 4), 1920-1980; 213564 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 6)
      Hedges
      Helleborus
      Herbals
    - Subjects: H (3 of 4), 1920-1980; 213565 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 7)
      Horticultural therapy
    - Subjects: H (4 of 4), 1920-1980; 213566 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 8)
      Hydrangea
      Hyacinthus
    - Subjects: I (1 of 2), 1920-1980; 211898 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 9)
      Ilex (holly)
      Iran: gardens
    - Subjects: I (2 of 2), 1920-1980; 213567 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 10)
      Iris
      Italy: gardens
    - Subjects: J-K, 1920-2000; 211899 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 11)
      Japanese gardens
      Knot gardens
    - Subjects: L (1-2 of 3), 1920-2000; 211908 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 12-13)
      Landscape Architecture
    - Subjects: L (3 of 3), 1920-2000; 213568 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 14)
    - Subjects: M, 1920-1980; 212170 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 1)
      Magnolia
    - Subjects: N, 1930-1990; 212173 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 2)
      Narcissus
      New York City: gardens
      North Carolina: gardens
    - Subjects: P (1 of 2), 1920-2000; 212181 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 3)
      Paeonias (peonies)
      Plant hunters
    - Subjects: P (2 of 2), 1920-2000; 213571 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 4)
      Perennial gardens
      Perennials
    - Subjects: R (1 of 3), 1920-2000; 212182 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 5)
      Ranunculus
      Rock gardens
    - Subjects: R (2 of 3), 1920-2000; 213572 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 6)
      Rockefeller Center gardens
      Rooftop gardens
    - Subjects: R (3 of 3), 1920-2000; 213573 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 7)
      Roses
    - Subjects: S (1 of 4), 1920-2000; 212184 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 8)
      Seaside gardens
      Seed industry
    - Subjects: S (2 of 4), 1920-2000; 213575 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 9)
      Shade gardening
      Shakespeare gardens
    - Subjects: S (3 of 4), 1920-2000; 213576 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 10)
      Street Trees
    - Subjects: S (4 of 4), 1920-2000; 213577 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 11)
      Sundials
      Syringa
    - Subjects: W, 1930-2006; 212187 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 12)
      Women
- Series IX. Memorabilia, 1900s-1998; 213285; 4.25 Linear feet
  Series IX contains a small amount of artifactual material from the HSNY, including awards given (ribbons, medals, and an inscribed silver bowl) and received (commemorative plaques), buttons and lapel pins, and some of the hardwood cases that held photographic lantern slides now found in subseries III.C and V.E.
  The smaller items in Series IX--armbands, buttons, ribbons, medals, bowl, printing plates, and diminutive award plaques--are housed in Boxes FF-13 and 83. The larger material--empty slide carousels and wooden cases, and an oblong award plaque--are housed in an oversized bankers box (11 x 15.5 x 25 inches), Box 84.
  - Armbands (7), 213304 (Offsite-box 105, Box FF-13, Folder 1)
    INTERNATIONAL FLOWER SHOW | OFFICIAL
  - Buttons & lapel pins (5), n.d.; 213305 (Offsite-box 105, Box FF-13, Folder 2)
    [1] NYFS | VOLUNTEER
    [2] MEMBER | HORTICULTURAL SOCIETY
    [3] GET GROWING | Join | the Horticultural | Society
    [4] PEOPLE FOR TREES | TREES FOR PEOPLE | H.S.N.Y. [with printed design for same]
    [5] CONTRIBUTOR [lapel pin]
  - Ribbons (7), n.d.; 213306 (Offsite-box 105, Box FF-13, Folder 3)
    [1] FIRST PLACE [blue]
    [2-3] SECOND | THE | NEW YORK | FLOWER SHOW | THE | HORTICULTURAL | SOCIETY | OF | NEW YORK [red] (2)
    [4-5] JUDGE | THE | NEW YORK | FLOWER SHOW | THE | HORTICULTURAL | SOCIETY | OF | NEW YORK [blue] (2)
    [6-7] CLERK | THE | NEW YORK | FLOWER SHOW | THE | HORTICULTURAL | SOCIETY | OF | NEW YORK [yellow] (2)
  - Awards: plaques (2), 1964, 1983; 213287 (Offsite-box 83, Object 1-2)
    Two wooden plaques:
    [1] INTERNATIONAL | FLOWER SHOW | NEW YORK | AWARDED TO | THE HORTICULTURAL SOCIETY OF NEW YORK | FOR | EDUCATIONAL CONTRIBUTION THROUGH THE | AMATEUR AREA | AT THE | INTERNATIONAL FLOWER SHOW | MARCH 1964
    [2] PRESENTED TO THE | HORTICULTURAL SOCIETY | OF NEW YORK | IN APPRECIATION OF THEIR | OUTSTANDING CONTRIBUTIONS | TO THE SUCCESS | OF OUR PROGRAM | TIP NEIGHBORHOOD HOUSE, INC. | OCTOBER 14, 1983
  - Award: bowl, n.d.; 213301 (Offsite-box 83, Object 3)
    Small silver bowl inscribed "THE HORTICULTURAL SOCIETY | OF NEW YORK AWARD | NEW YORK FLOWER SHOW."
  - Medals: Inscribed (11), 1987, 1996; 213299 (Offsite-box 83, Object 4)
    [1] THE NATALIE PETERS WEBSTER MEDAL; [reverse] AWARDED TO A MEMBER OR MEMBER CLUB FOR FINDING UNUSUAL PLANT MATERIAL | ENCOURAGING ITS CREATIVE USE AND ASSURING ITS AVAILABILITY | HENRIETTA E. S. LOCKWOOD | 1987 [gold; large format]
    [2] AWARDED TO | SLEEPY HOLLOW RESTORATION INC. | 1987 | NY FLOWER SHOW [gold]
    [3] AWARDED TO | TOM THURSTON & CO. | 1987 | NY FLOWER SHOW [gold]
    [4] AWARDED TO | MRS. JOHN E. | LOCKWOOD | on April 17, 1996 | flor her devotion | to the library [gold]
    [5] AWARDED TO | 1st PLACE | THE | NEW YORK | FLOWER SHOW [gold]
    [6-8] AWARDED TO | 2nd PLACE | THE | NEW YORK | FLOWER SHOW [silver] (3 copies)
    [9-11] AWARDED TO | 3rd PLACE | THE | NEW YORK | FLOWER SHOW [bronze] (3 copies)
  - Medals: Blank (16), n.d.; 213300 (Offsite-box 83, Object 5)
    Sixteen copies of a medal (14 bronze, 2 gold) with a blank reverse and "HORTICULTURAL SOCIETY OF NEW YORK | 1902" seal on obverse.
  - Printing plates (2), n.d.; 213312 (Offsite-box 83, Object 6-7)
    Two small woodblock printing plates, one with Horticultural Society of New York seal, the other with logo for "People for Trees | Trees for People" (see box FF-13, folder 2, for lapel pin with same design).
  - Award: plaque [Oversize], 1998 April; 213288 (Offsite-box 84, Object 1)
    GREENBRANCHES-SARATOGA BRANCH | LIBRARY PARTNERSHIP PROJECT | OF THE HORTICULTURAL SOCIETY OF N.Y. | BROOKLYN PUBLIC LIBRARY & BROOKLYN BOTANIC GARDEN | APRIL 1998.
    With reproduction of Linda Locke's article, "A Branch Blooms in Brooklyn," from the April 1998 issue of American Libraries: The Magazine of the American Library Association.
  - Photographic slide carousels (2) [Oversize], 1960s-1970s; 213302 (Offsite-box 84, Object 2-3)
    Two empty Kodak photographic slide carousel trays in their boxes, one marked "BPFS" for "Bryant Park Flower Show." The slides may be found in Subseries III.C.
  - Photographic lantern slide cases (4) [Oversize], 1900s; 213303 (Offsite-box 84, Object 4-7)
    Four empty boxes (one is a leather-like case, three are wood) that held the photographic lantern slides found in Subseries III.C and V.E.